Pablo Rodrigo Frandalozo Darde

pablodarde@gmail.com +55 54 996 65 46 11 https://darde.github.io

Summary

Software engineer and architect, specialist in technologies such as ReactJS, Redux, Vue, Jest, Vanilla JavaScript (es5, es6, es7), TypeScript, CSS3, Tailwindcss, and others. Backend engineer working with NodeJS, express, NextJS, (RestFul API), MongoDB, GraphQL, Postgres. I work with Git, Circle Ci, and Docker. I'm an agile developer formed with XP principles. Leadership mentoring experience.

Specialization Overview

- * TDD (test-driven development with Moca, Jest, and React Testing Library) * Integration test with Cypress/Selenium
- * ReactJS (advanced level, hooks, Jest, RTL)
- * Clean Code/Clean Architecture
- * S.O.L.I.D. principles

Complementary skills

- * Micro frontends
- * Storybook
- * ThreeJS (React Three Fiber/React Three Drei)
- * AWS (Amplify, S3, Lambda, Cloudfront, RDS, Dynamo)/ GCP (Sk8, functions, Firebase)

Professional Experience

Remedy Product Studio - Technical Lead | December 2023 - Present

Technologies

At Remedy I'm working as a Tech Lead in a distributed team (Europe, US, and Latin America). I have worked as React Native (iOS) developer on my last project, and I'm currently working as a Tech Lead in a VueJS/Python (Fast API) project.

Still Life Inc. - Lead Frontend Engineer | October 2022 - November 2023

Technologies

JavaScript, React Native (iOS/Android) developer, React (hooks), Redux, NodeJS, SOLID, AWS S3,

CDN, (Cloudfront), Postgres, MongoDB, TypeScript

Projects

At Still Life I was one lead frontend engineer and full-stack developer. I worked making important architecture decisions to improve an application that helps users to keep focused and relaxed during

the day. The app offers some breath challenges using songs and audio texts. In this project, my main role was frontend specialist and full-stack engineer developing React-Native, React-Redux, GraphQL (Frontend), NodeJS, Postgres, and Clerk for authentication (Backend). Periodically we release new versions using the Apple TestFlight tool to allow guests and developers to test new features.

Pipefy - Principal Software Engineer | October 2021 - October 2022

Technologies

JavaScript, TypeScript, React (hooks), Redux, GraphQL, Webpack, Jest, CSS3, NodeJS,

NextJS (V. 13+), Clean Architecture, SOLID, TDD, Datadog, SonarQube, Sentry, SaaS,

Microservices, Postgres

Projects

At Pipefy, I didn't work on a specific project, instead, I worked as a Principal Engineer helping the feature teams to plan and develop new features. I was responsible for leading a group of developers building features through the correct engineering processes. I splitted my time on 40% hands-on coding, and 60% mentoring, planning, and pairing with other developers. I worked together with the Frontend Platform Team to create new internal products for developers. I also had a weekly meeting with the CTO and other Principals to keep the engineering strategies aligned. At Pipefy I also set up some DataDog alarms and improved the errors handling using tools like Sentry. I also proposed and implemented a Quality Assurance improvement by adding the Sonarqube tool in the Gitlab CI/CI pipeline.

At Pipefy I organized an Internal Mentoring Program together with the People Team to leverage the technical skills of some developers.

X-Team - Software Engineer | December 2020 - October 2021

Technologies

JavaScript, React, Redux, Webpack, Jest, CSS3, NodeJS, Travis, NextJS (V 13+), SaaS,

Microservices, Postgres, MongoDB, TypeScript

Projects

At X-Team I worked as a lead frontend engineer. I worked with a gym application development with NextJS, REST, NodeJS, and Jasmine. My main responsibility was to maintain the frontend code working as expected, and without bugs. Ensure we had good testing coverage, besides pairing with other developers. I was also responsible for releasing a big feature where I built a third party integration with a song library called "feed.fm".

RD Station - Senior Software Engineer | Jun 2017 - Dec 2020

Technologies

JavaScript, React, Redux, Webpack, Jest, RTL, Cypress, CSS3, Micro frontends, NodeJS, Ruby on Rails, CI/CD, Docker, AWS CloudFront, AWS S3, GCP, Elastic Stack, Datadog, Clean Architecture, SOLID, TDD, Software Architecture, SaaS, Microservices, Postgres, TypeScript

Projects

Drag and Drop Editor (Landing Pages, Pop Ups, Email, Forms)

I built a drag and drop editor from scratch. This is one of the most important features in the company and keeps delivering great value. This project was built with Vanilla JavaScript, and React/Redux. Has Clean Architecture and SOLID concepts in its construction. My main responsibilities was to code frontend applications using the best architectural practices. Also I spent 30% to 40% of my time mentoring and pairing with junior, mid-levels, and seniors developers. In this project I made important architectural decisions.

Micro frontend Orchestrator (Front hub)

Our front-end applications were high coupled with the Ruby back-end monolith. So we presented to our managers a solution to allow our developers to build front-end applications decoupled from the monolith and with its own repo, own CI/CI pipelines (micro frontends), and totally independently from the legacy code. This increased the speed and productivity of our front end developers. This project is scaling very fast today.

I also implemented some Elastic Stack Kibana dashboards to get observability on frontend applications.

Daitan Group - Front end Specialist | May 2016 - Jul 2017

Technologies

JavaScript, React, Redux, Webpack, CSS3, Micro frontends, NodeJS, Ruby, CI/CD, Docker, AWS S3, AWS Cloudfront

Projects

Encrypted chat for american banks

I worked with a hybrid team (Brazil - São Paulo, and the United States - Palo Alto company). My main role at Daitan was lead frontend engineer. I was responsible for planning and designing the UI for 3rd party integrations such as Jira, Github, Zapier, among others. I worked on an encrypted chat to American Banks. We used Java and Spring on the Backend side, and React and React-Redux on the Frontend site.

SAP - Senior JavaScript Developer | May 2015 - May 2016

Technologies

JavaScript, Java JSF, Github, Screen reader JAWS, Functional Testing

Projects

Accessibility enhancement in complex interfaces.

I worked as a JavaScript developer improving accessibility on a German government website. Additionally, I was the lead tester on this project. My main role at SAP was senior developer and tester. We used JAVA JSF templates, pure JavaScript, and Juice (a proprietary JavaScript library). I also used tools like JAWS screen reader to test improvements on accessibility. We worked together with an Indian team.

PUCRS - Technical Lead | Dec 2013 - Jan 2015

Technologies

JavaScript, Scrum, Project Management, mySql

Projects

Creation, planning, and development of the University Websites

I led a team responsible for delivering internal web applications to the University. We worked with agile methodologies like Scrum with well defined sprints and goals. I worked together with a Product Manager, and a Designer. During this time we delivered many products, including the main University website.

Front end Developer and Flash Programmer

ago 2007 - dic 2013

. . .

Education

Bachelor of Software Engineering, Unicesumar University, February 2021 (Complete)

Projects

Sveltekit project to Educative Inc learning platform. This project use Server Side Rendring technologies by using Svelte/Sveltekit. You can check it out in the following address.

https://svelteflix.vercel.app/